Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  - Sub-subseries 6: Virginia recordings - Bluefield, Lodi, and Saltville
    - 354 / Press Smith / Bluefield, VA, August 5, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0846; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      Press [Preston] Smith (Hobart Smith's brother), at the home of D[?] S[?], Bluefield, Virginia. Topics include: Saltville, preaching, family, etc.
    - 355 / 1180 / John Gallagher / Saltville, August 6, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0860; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, two track, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: guitar instrumentals, place names, train. All songs on Side 2 are fragments. Recorded in Saltville, Virginia.
      - Side 1
      - 1. Train at Duel's
      - 2. Charming Betsy
        With front and end talk
      - 3. Ginny Put the Kettle On
      - 4. Nigger Blues
        Out of E from Andy Flanagan and talking [?]
      - 5. Place names
        Good story about Broady B[?]
      - Side 2
      - 1. Place names on his grandfather who fought for North; on his grandfather who fought for South
      - 2. Yankee Doodle Dandy
      - 3. Dixie (fragment)
      - 4. Railroad Bill
      - 5. Coney Isle
      - 6. Brown Skin Blues
      - 7. Casey Jones
    - 356 / 1185 / John Gallagher / Earl Stacey / Ben Dinsmore / Saltville, August 6, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0847; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, two track, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: guitar and dulcimer instrumentals, Lomax visit.
      - 1. Brown Skin Blues - John Gallagher
      - 2. Black Mammy Blues - Earl Stacey
      - 3. Steppin' the Frets - Earl Stacey
      - 4. Sing Low - Ben Dinsmore, in Cedar Branch
      - 5. [unidentified]
      - 6. I Want to Be in That Number [Saints Go Marching In?]
      - 7. [unidentified]
      - 8. How Lomax got him up at 5 a.m. to record and put him on record without even giving him a copy [?] Hob's check [?]
    - 357 / 1186 / Ben Dinsmore (dulcimer) / Saltville, August 6, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0848; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Ben Dinsmore, dulcimer instrumentals
      - Rock of Ages
      - Down at Cross
      - When the Roll is Called Up Yonder
      - Talk about [?]
      - Minor chord (his own)
      - Jesus Hold My Hand
      - Talk on getting religion
      - Black Eyed Susie
      - [unidentified]
      - Alabama Gals
      - John Henry
      - Boil Them Cabbage Down
    - 358 / 1187 / Ben Dinsmore (dulcimer) / Saltville, August 6, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0849; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      - Talk on dulcimer and Bible
      - What a Friend We Have in Jesus
      - What're We Gonna Do With the Baby O
      - Talk on s[?] he was three and story
    - 359 / 1188 / Carl Gray (fretless banjo), August 7, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0850; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Carl Gray, 64 years old, plays fretless banjo. According to a note on the tape box back, the date given on the recording is wrong; it should be August 7, 1965.
    - 360 / John and Kansas Davison / Saltville, August 7, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0851; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 5 in.
      Religious duets. John is accompanied by Kansas on accordion. They live in Saltville, Virginia. According to a note on the tape box back, the tapes were recorded on two 5-inch reels and spliced together.
    - 361 / John and Kansas Davison / Saltville, August 7, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0852; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Religious duets. John is accompanied by Kansas on accordion and guitar. The Davisons live in Saltville, Virginia. According to a note on the tape box back, the tapes were recorded on two 5-inch reels and spliced together.
    - 362 / Charles Holmes, Lodi / Carl Gray, Saltville, August 7-8, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0853; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, mono; 7 in.
      Contents: banjo instrumentals (Holmes); banjo and harmonica instrumentals (Gray). Holmes was recorded on August 7, and Gray was recorded on August 8. Holmes was from Lodi, Virginia, and Carl Gray was from Saltville, Virginia. Recorded on a Tandberg tape deck.
      - 1. John Henry - Charles Holmes
      - 2. Cindy - Charles Holmes
      - 3. Shot Little Lulu - Charles Holmes
      - 4. Casey Jones - Carl Gray
      - 5. Cluck Old Hen - Carl Gray
      - 6. I Went to the River - Carl Gray
      - 7. Believer's [?] Train - Carl Gray
      - 8. New River Train [first time] - Carl Gray
      - 9. New River Train [second time] - Carl Gray
      - 10. Runnin' That Nigger With a Barton [?] Knife - Carl Gray
      - 11. John Henry [first time] - Carl Gray
      - 12. John Henry [second time] - Carl Gray
      - 13. Uncloudy Day (fragment) - Carl Gray
      - 14. Cripple Creek - Carl Gray
      - 15. Candy Girls - Carl Gray
      - 16. Casey Jones - Carl Gray
      - 17. What a Sorrow Will Be There - Carl Gray
      - 18. Lost Train Blues - Carl Gray
    - 363 / Fred Gallagher and family / Saltville / 118[?], August 8, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0854; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, stereo; 7 in.
      Recorded in Saltville, Virginia, at John Gallagher's. Jackson's note on the tape box back: "read gospel songs from type and print NB [notebook] sitting."
      - 1. I'll Wear a White Robe
      - 2. Wayfaring Pilgrim
      - 3. We Have Friends in Glory Land
      - 4. Lord I Cannot Walk Alone
      - 5. I See a Bridge (no book, standing up)
      - 6. The Family Who Prays (sitting, book)
      - 7. Thank Him For What He Has Done
    - 364 / 1193 / Fred Gallagher / Saltville, August 8, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0856; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, quarter track, mono; 5 in.
      Contents: songs and instrumentals. A note on the tape box back: "he also plays banjo - ask for John Harding."
      - 1. Drunkard's Hiccups
        Fiddle
      - 2. Buffalo Girls
      - 3. When the Stars Begin to Fall
        Guitar and vocal
      - 4. Takin' Names [?]
      - 5. Nine-Pound Hammer
        Guitar
      - 6. Rusty Rag
      - 7. El Paso
        Guitar; in the key of C
      - 8. Railroad Bill
      - 9. K.C. Whistle
        Guitar; "Spanish"
    - 365 / 1194 / Holmes / Lodi, Va. / 2, August 9, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0857; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Contents: banjo and guitar instrumentals and vocals. Recorded in Lodi, Virginia, at the home of Charles Holmes. Charles Holmes, bass; Sam Holmes, guitar; then Sam on bass and Charles Holmes on guitar; then Charles takes banjo and Sam guitar, then Charles on bass and Sam guitar.
    - 366 / 1198 / Holmes / Lodi, Va., August 9, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0859; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Contents: banjo and guitar instrumentals and vocals. Recorded in Lodi, Virginia, at the home of Charles Holmes. Charles plays fretless banjo.
      - 1. Walkin' in the Parlor
      - 2. Fly Around My Black Eyed Girl
      - 3. Old 97
      - 4. Uncloudy Day
      - 5. Cindy
      - 6. New River Train
      - 7. Red Wing
      - 8. [?]
      - 9. Fly Around My Blue Eyed Girl
        With Sam on guitar
      - 10. Shout Little Lulu - Sam, guitar solo
      - 11. Railroad Bill - Sam, guitar solo
      - 12. She[?]
      - 13. Arkansas Traveler
      - 14. Man Who Fell Out of Cornfield
    - 367 / 1196 / Holmes / Lodi, Va. / 3, August 9, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0858; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono and stereo; 5 in.
      Contents: banjo and guitar instrumentals and vocals. According to notes on the tape box back, Sam Holmes is playing a fretless that Jackson got from Carl Gray. The first three songs were recorded in mono, and the rest in stereo. At some point during the recording thunder could be heard outside.
      - 1. Train #9
      - 2. Cripple Creek (?)
      - 3. Poor Ellen Smith
        First p[?], then rapping
      - 4. Comin' Around the Mountain - Sam, on guitar
      - 5. Shed house in among back yard [?] - Sam, vocal
      - 6. 5's how the heck does he survive - Sam, vocal
      - 7. Soldier's Joy - Sam, guitar; Carl, bass
      - 8. Arkansas Traveler - Sam, guitar; Carl, bass
      - 9. New River Train - Sam, guitar; Carl, bass
      - 10. Mess - Sam, guitar; Carl, bass
      - 11. Wildwood Flower - Sam, guitar; Carl, bass
      - 12. Willow Garden - Sam, solo
      - 13. Little Jimmy Brown
      - 14. I'm Going to the Shack [?]
      - 15. A Hundred Miles from Home
      - 16. Hand Me Down My Walking Cane
    - 368 / 1197 / Holmes / Lodi, Va. / 4, August 9, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0861; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/ ips half track, stereo; 5 in.
      Sam and Charlie Holmes. Contents: banjo and guitar instrumentals and vocals.
      - 1. Groundhog
      - 2. Ellen Smith
      - 3. Sleep in Your Barn Tonight Mister
      - 4. Sleep in Your Barn Tonight Mister
      - 5. Walkin' in the Parlor
      - 6. Little Log Cabin in the Lane
      - 7. Uncloudy Day
      - 8. Johnson Boy
      - 9. [unidentified]
      - 10. Hand Me Down My Walkin' Cane
      - 11. Little Birdie
      - 12. Wildwood Flower
      - 13. In the Pines
      - 14. In the Pines
        Vocal
      - 15. Sourwood Mountain
      - 16. #9 Hammer
      - 17. Cumberland Gap
      - 18. New River Train
      - 19. New River Train
    - Saltville, VA / Mountain View, Ark. / Misc. #9, 1964-1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0951; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - Saltville / #1 / 1965, August 6-7, 1965, August 9, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0925; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      A compilation of field recordings.
      - 1. John Henry - Carl Gray, August 7, 1965
        See source recording SR0850.
      - 2. Cripple Creek - Carl Gray, August 7, 1965
      - 3. What a Friend We Have in Jesus - Ben Dinsmore, August 6, 1965
        See source recording SR0849.
      - 4. What You Gonna Do With the Baby O - Ben Dinsmore, August 6, 1965
      - 5. Don't You Hear Them Bells No Ringin' - Ben Dinsmore, August 6, 1965
      - 6. Alabama Gal - Dinsmore, August 6, 1965
        See source recording SR0848.
      - 7. John Henry, August 6, 1965
      - 8. Ginny Put the Kettle On - John Gallagher, August 6, 1965
      - 9. Nigger Blues
        Including talk
      - 10. Walkin' in the Parlor - Charlie Holmes, banjo, August 9, 1965
      - 11. Fly Around My Blue-Eyed Gal - Charlie and Sam Holmes
      - 12. Story about man who "fell out of cornfield" - Sam Holmes
      - 13. Fly Away Little Birdie - Sam Holmes, banjo; C.W. Holmes, guitar, August 9, 1965
        See source recording SR0857.
      - 14. White House Blues - Sam Holmes, vocal
      - 15. Ground Hog - Sam Holmes, guitar; Charlie Holmes, banjo, August 9, 1965
        See source recording SR0858.
      - 16. Walkin' in the Parlor - Sam Holmes; Charlie Holmes, August 9, 1965
      - 17. In the Pines - Sam Holmes; Charlie Holmes
    - Holmes / Gallagher / Saltville, June 14, 1964, August 7-9, 1965, AFC 2011/009: SR0924; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Willow Garden - Sam Holmes, August 9, 1965
      - Little Jimmy Brown - Sam Holmes, August 9, 1965
      - When the Stars Begin to Fall - Fred Gallagher, August 8, 1965
        See source recording SR0856.
      - Takin' Names [?] - Fred Gallagher, August 8, 1965
      - Railroad Bill - Fred Gallagher, August 8, 1965
      - K.C. Whistle - Fred Gallagher, August 8, 1965
      - Casey Jones (guitar) - Carl Gray, August 8, 1965
        See source recording SR0853.
      - Cripple Creek (guitar) - Carl Gray, August 8, 1965
      - Casey Jones (harp) - Carl Gray, August 8, 1965
      - Lost Train Blues (harp) - Carl Gray, August 8, 1965
      - Gracious Mercy [?] - John and Kansas Davison, August 7, 1965
        See source recording SR0852.
      - As You Travel Down [?] (It's a Lonesome Road to Travel) - John and Kansas Davison, August 7, 1965
      - Amazing Grace - John and Kansas Davison, August 7, 1965
      - Johnson's in the White House - John and Kansas Davison, August 7, 1965
        Fragment. See source recording SR0852.
      - House of David Blues - John Gallagher, June 14, 1964
        See source recording SR0807.
      - Talk on his [?] - John Gallagher, June 14, 1964
      - Railroad Bill - John Gallagher, June 14, 1964
      - K.C. Whistle - Jim Gallagher, June 14, 1964
        Open tuning [on guitar?]. See source recording SR0807.
      - Ginny Put the Kettle On - John Gallagher, June 14, 1964
      - Railroad Bill - John Gallagher, June 14, 1964
      - Amazing Grace - John Gallagher, June 14, 1964
  - Sub-subseries 7: Southeast Asia Oral History Project
    The Southeast Asia Oral History Project is an unfinished project by Bruce Jackson, focused on interviews with Vietnam war veterans.
    - 1776 / Seaohp #1 / Ron Garneau #1 / interviewed by Drumlevitch, June 17, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0910; 1 sound tape reel (25 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips; 5 in.
      Tape 1, reel 1 transcribed. Ron Garneau, interviewed by Seymour Drumlevitch. The speed may be a little slower (as noted in the documentation).
    - 1777 / Seaohp #2 / Garneau #2 / and Kurt #2 / interviewed by Drumlevitch, June 25, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0911; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      See note for SR0910.
      - Ron Garneau / tape II reel 1 of I / W&[??]rst Place / Background and two stories / 10-15 minutes
      - Kurt / tape II reel 1 summarized
    - 1778 / Seaohp #3 / Kirk and anonymous / interviewed by Drumlevitch, possibly July 11, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0912; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      See note for SR0910. Anonymous Source 2 / Tape I, reel II / transcribed; Kirk / tape I reel II / transcribed
    - 1779 / Seaohp #4 / Anonymous #1 / interviewed by Drumlevitch, possibly July 5, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0913; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      See note for SR0910. Anonymous Source #1 / Reel 1 tape 1 / to be remastered cut out miscellaneous conversation / transcribed up to 438 [number on the tape counter] where it's too hard to hear
    - 1780 / Seaohp #5 / Kurt / anonymous #2 / interviewed by Drumlevitch, possibly July 11, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0914; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
      See note for SR0910. Tape I Reel I / transcribed
    - 1781 / Seaohp #6 / Tom / interviewed by Drumlevitch, circa 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0915; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
    - Tapes 1-2 (Both Sides) / G. Coons / VA Hospital / Copley, August 30, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0916; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - Seaohp / Pat Kelly / Buffalo / (Bruce Jackson), September 21, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0917; 1 sound cassette (120 min.): analog
      See note for SR0910. Pat Kelly at 96 Rumsey / Diane Christian, Barbara Copley, Bruce Jackson
    - Seaohp / Pat Kelly / Gene Bender, New Orleans / (Bruce Jackson) / 10, September 23, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0918; 1 sound cassette: analog
      See note for SR0910. Gene Bender, interviewed by Bruce Jackson
    - 1783 / Dan Amisone, September 21, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0960; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - 1784 / Coons, August 30, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0909; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, two track, mono; 5 in.
      G. Coons, Buffalo VA Hospital. Interviewed by B. Copley.
    - 1785 / Gene Bender / Austin, circa 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0961; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Gene Bender, recorded by himself, in Austin.
    - 1786 / Pat Kelly, September 21, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0962; 1 sound tape reel: analog, two track, mono; 7 in.
      Pat Kelly, at 96 Rumsey; interviewed by Bruce Jackson. Also present: Barbara Copley and Diane Christian.
    - 1787 / Bob Poole and Gene Bender, September 23-24, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0963; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Side 1
      - Bob Poole, recorded in New Orleans, September 24, 1976
        First part of Side 1 on cassette has been lost (Jackson's note).
      - Side 2
      - Gene Bender, recorded in New Orleans, September 23, 1976
    - 1788 / Kurtzke and Levin, October 10, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0964; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Larry Kurtzke and Peter Levin, recorded by Barbara Copley.
    - 1789 / Kurtzke and Levin, October 10, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0965; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Larry Kurtzke and Peter Levin, assumed to have been recorded by Barbara Copley.
    - Ed. Serba / Vet Office SUNYAB [SUNY at Buffalo] / Copley / 10-20-76, October 20, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0941; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Possibly an interview by Barbara Copley.
    - 1782 / Ted Podkul / Barbara Copley / 9-30-76, September 30, 1976, AFC 2011/009: SR0959; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, two track; 7 in.
      Ted Podkul, interviewed at his home by Barbara Copley.
  - Sub-subseries 8: William August May
    - 28 / Sync for 80-85 / William August May, circa 1978-1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1224; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - 29 / Sync for 86-88 / William August may, circa 1978-1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1225; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - 30 / William August May: wild sound at wharf; last sync int., circa 1978-1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1226; 1 sound cassette (60 min.): analog
    - 1 / Wild Sound at Dock / Wm A May in Cal, December 30, 1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1227; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - 2 / Sync track, circa 1978-1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1228; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - William August May #1 / San Francisco, BJ and DC, March 4 or 5, 1978, AFC 2011/009: SR1229; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Both dates are on the documentation.
    - William August May / San Francisco, BJ and DC, March 4, 1978, AFC 2011/009: SR1230; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
      Side A is noted as "William A May Side 3."
    - 4 / William A. May / in Ca- and at Princeton by the Sea, December 30, 1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1231; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - 5 / William A. May / in Ca- and at Princeton by the Sea, December 30, 1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1232; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
    - 6 / William A. May, December 30, 1979, AFC 2011/009: SR1233; 1 sound cassette (90 min.): analog
  - Sub-subseries 9: William Kunstler [unfinished documentary]
    - 818 / Political Cases and Unpopular Causes / William Kunstler and Gerald Lefcourt / Tape #1, circa 1988, AFC 2011/009: SR0638; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
    - 815 / Political Cases and Unpopular Causes / William Kunstler and Gerald Lefcourt / Tape #2, circa 1988, AFC 2011/009: SR0635; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
  - Subseries 2: Newport Folk Festival recordings
  - Sub-subseries 1: Newport Folk Festival, 1963, July 26-28, 1963
    - 001 / 63 2E / Reel B1 - Bluegrass concert, July 26, 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0001; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Watermelon on the Vine - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
      - Mule Skinner Blues - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
      - Uncle Pen - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
      - Devil's Dream - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys (Keith)
      - Molly and Tenbrooks - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
      - I Am a Pilgrim - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
      - Rawhide - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
      - Few [?] Days - Raun MacKinnon
      - Pressed Seaman - Raun MacKinnon
      - Old Grey Coat - Raun MacKinnon
      - You're Gonna Miss Me - Raun MacKinnon
    - 002 / 63 2E / Reel B2 - Peabody, July 26, 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0002; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      Reel 2; continued from SR0001.
      - Medgar Evers Lullabye - Raun MacKinnon
      - Crow Jane - Brownie McGhee and Sonny Terry
      - I Woke Up This Morning - Brownie McGhee and Sonny Terry
      - If You Don't Want to Be My Neighbor - Brownie McGhee and Sonny Terry
      - Kansas City - Brownie McGhee and Sonny Terry
      - [nine songs] - Hélène Baillargeon and Jean Carignan
        All songs appear to be in French
    - 003 / 63 2E / Reel B3 / Peter, Paul and Mary, July 26, 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0003; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Go Tell It on the Mountain
      - A Soul Cake [A Soalin']
      - Old Blue
      - Old Blue
        Parody
      - 500 Miles
      - Puff the Magic Dragon
      - Blowing in the Wind
      - If I Had My Way
      - The Hammer Song [If I Had a Hammer]
    - 004 / 63 2E / Reel B4, July 26, 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0004; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Going to Make Joy My Home - Freedom Singers
      - Been Down Onto the South - Freedom Singers
      - Woke Up This Morning - Freedom Singers
      - Get On Board, [?] Children - Freedom Singers
      - Guide My Feet - Freedom Singers
      - Dowie Dens of Yarrow - Jean Redpath
      - Muckin' o' Geordie's Byre - Jean Redpath
      - Song of the Seals - Jean Redpath
    - 005 / 63 2E / Reel B5, July 26, 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0005; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Everyday Dirt - Doc Watson
        A Dave McCarn song
      - Train That Carried My Girl from Town - Doc Watson
      - Country Blues - Doc Watson
      - What Does the Deep Sea Say - Doc Watson with Bill Monroe
      - What Would You Give in Exchange for Your Soul - Doc Watson with Bill Monroe
      - Feast Here Tonight [Have a Feast Here Tonight] - Doc Watson with Bill Monroe
      - Talking III WW [Talkin' World War III Blues] - Bob Dylan
      - With God on Our Side - Bob Dylan
    - 006 / 63 2E / Reel B6, July 26, 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0006; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Only a Pawn in Their Game (Medgar Evers) - Bob Dylan
      - Talking Birch Society [Talkin' John Birch Society Blues] - Bob Dylan
      - Hard Rain's Gonna Fall - Bob Dylan
      - Blowing in the Wind - Bob Dylan, Pete Seeger, Freedom Singers, Peter, Paul and Mary, and Joan Baez
        Finale
      - We Shall Overcome - Bob Dylan, Pete Seeger, Freedom Singers, Peter, Paul and Mary, and Joan Baez
    - 007 / 63 3W / Reel B7 - Bluegrass, July 27, 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0007; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips and 7 1/2 ips; 7 in.
      - Bill Clifton, MC
      - Instrumental - unidentified performer(s)
      - She Left Me Standing on the Mountain (Bluebird) [Gonna Find Me A Bluebird?] - Jim and Jesse [McReynolds]
      - My Heart is Broken For You - Wiley and Zeke Morris [Morris Brothers]
      - Salty Dog - Wiley and Zeke Morris [Morris Brothers]
      - Mike Seeger, MC
      - [?] - Jean Carignan
        "Tune from my father"
      - Cape Breton [?] - Jean Carignan
      - Prince Edward Island - Jean Carignan
        Scotch [Scottish]
      - Pop! Goes the Weasel - Jean Carignan
        Trick fiddling
    - 008 / 63 3W / Reel B8 - Bluegrass, July 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0008; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - Paddy on the Turnpike - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
        Fiddle tune
      - Pike Country Breakdown - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys (banjo - Brad Keith)
        Processor's note: Bill Keith's middle name as Bradford, and Bill Monroe called him "Brad" (Neil V. Rosenberg and Charles K. Wolfe, The Music of Bill Monroe, (Champaign, IL: University of Illinois Press, 2007), 149.
      - Rawhide - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys
      - Get Up John - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys (mandolin - Bill Monroe)
      - Will You Be Loving Another Man - Bill Monroe and his Blue Grass Boys [vocal - Bill Monroe?]
      - Pretty Fair Maiden in the Garden [Pretty Fair Maid in the Garden] - Ralph Rinzler and Bill Clifton
      - You Give Me Your Love and I'll Give You Mine - Wiley and Zeke Morris [Morris Brothers]
      - Katy Hill - Tex Logan
        Tune played in the key of G
      - Cotton-Eyed Joe - Tex Logan, vocal
        Square dance tune
    - 009 / 63 3W / Reel B9 - Bluegrass, July 1963, AFC 2011/009: SR0009; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      - I Wonder How the Old Folks Are at Home - Mac Wiseman and the Country Boys
      - Love Letters in the Sand - Mac Wiseman and the Country Boys
      - Can't You Hear Me Calling - Mac Wiseman and the Country Boys, with Bill Monroe